<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2023-12-28T19:57:23-06:00</updated><id>/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Video Grandpa</title><subtitle>Get off my lawn</subtitle><author><name>Chris Ostertag</name></author><entry><title type="html">How to Back Up Everything</title><link href="/how-to-back-up-everything/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How to Back Up Everything" /><published>2023-12-27T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2023-12-27T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>/how-to-back-up-everything</id><content type="html" xml:base="/how-to-back-up-everything/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.unsplash.com/photo-1575729853562-e3ad7084c28d?ixlib=rb-1.2.1&amp;amp;q=80&amp;amp;fm=jpg&amp;amp;crop=edges&amp;amp;cs=tinysrgb&amp;amp;fit=max&amp;amp;ixid=eyJhcHBfaWQiOjExNzczfQ&amp;amp;w=1000&quot; alt=&quot;a hard drive laying on a wooden table&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We collectively generate over a trillion digital photos a year. Many of them are pretty worthless: blurry concert videos, 70 versions of the same landscape, reference photos of groceries you need someone to pick up. But mixed in there are our most cherished memories - births, weddings, friends and family who may no longer be with us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How do we make sure that these moments are safely preserved? It can seem daunting and expensive, but it doesn’t have to be! Here’s how to make sure your data will be there when you need it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-3-2-1-rule&quot;&gt;The 3-2-1 rule&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Data is not properly backed up unless it follows the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.backblaze.com/blog/the-3-2-1-backup-strategy/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;3-2-1 Rule&lt;/a&gt;: it’s in &lt;strong&gt;three&lt;/strong&gt; places, &lt;strong&gt;two&lt;/strong&gt; onsite (but on different mediums) and &lt;strong&gt;one&lt;/strong&gt; offsite. This protects you against most scenarios short of global catastrophe. House fire? You’ve still got the offsite backup. Laptop stolen? You’ve still got the second onsite and the offsite. The Cloud falls out of the sky? You still have two copies onsite.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-onsite-backup&quot;&gt;The onsite backup&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re going to assume that you have a computer - laptop, desktop, whatever - that’s the primary location for all your data. This is the first of our three data locations, and the one where you normally access the files.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You then need to back up those files to a &lt;strong&gt;separate&lt;/strong&gt; location - a second hard drive in the same machine doesn’t count, nor does a mirrored RAID count as two locations (I see you, production people).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The simplest solution is an external drive. Buy &lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/3TYH33B&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;a good one&lt;/a&gt; and set yourself a calendar reminder to copy files to it. Don’t wait too long - drives sitting on shelves are not a good long-term storage solution, and should be plugged in at least once every six months  to confirm they’re still working right (I prefer once a month). When you’re not using it, it should &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt; be stored with the computer it’s backing up - put it in a separate room.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to get more advanced, you can use network-attached storage in place of an external drive. I personally use &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.synology.com/en-us/products/series/home&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Synology&lt;/a&gt; devices and have for years. I like them because you don’t have to be a sysadmin to set them up, they do &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.synology.com/en-us/solution/replacement_for_external_storage&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;all kinds of great stuff in addition to storage&lt;/a&gt;, and they’re reliable. For example, you could use the Photo Station function to serve up galleries of your whole photo library to any device on your network.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;kg-card kg-image-card kg-card-hascaption&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/posts/image.png&quot; class=&quot;kg-image&quot; alt=&quot;A gallery of images of my cat&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;An album of my old cat, served by Synology Photo Station&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-right-software&quot;&gt;The right software&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you perform file copies, and especially backups, it’s important to use the right software. Otherwise it’s easy to get something wrong, especially when dealing with a lot of files. I use &lt;a href=&quot;https://freefilesync.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;FreeFileSync&lt;/a&gt; for my backups - it can easily tell what’s been copied vs what still needs to be, and can check to make sure your copies are exactly the same as the originals and free of any corruption. And it works just fine with either external drives or network storage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;kg-card kg-image-card kg-card-hascaption&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/posts/image-2.png&quot; class=&quot;kg-image&quot; alt=&quot;A screenshot of the FreeFileSync application showing options for file validation and synchronization&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;You can choose options in FreeFileSync for file validation and synchronization&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-offsite-backup&quot;&gt;The offsite backup&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OK, so you’ve got your two - your primary data location plus one onsite backup. But what about that offsite? It’s time for The Cloud!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a lot of options for providers but I use &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.backblaze.com/cloud-backup&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Backblaze&lt;/a&gt;. They offer unlimited backup of one computer for $99/year, which is the best pricing you’ll find among the reputable vendors. Once you’ve installed and configured Backblaze, it works in the background - anything added to your computer is also backed up to the cloud. I have about 12TB of my personal data with them, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.backblaze.com/b2/case-studies/austin-city-limits.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;at work we use their B2 product&lt;/a&gt; to house hundreds of TB’s more. I know the team there, like what they do, and trust them with my data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But don’t trust too much! Another feature I like is their &lt;a href=&quot;https://help.backblaze.com/hc/en-us/articles/217666498-Security-Settings-Win-&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;option&lt;/a&gt; to use your own Private Encryption Key that Backblaze does not store. This is great because it means that they can’t decrypt your data unless you enter your key. Since data privacy laws and regulations are still kind of a mess, &lt;strong&gt;I strongly recommend not storing anything sensitive in the cloud without encryption that you and you alone control.&lt;/strong&gt; Don’t think your family photos are sensitive? Then maybe you won’t mind when &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nbcnews.com/tech/internet/facial-recognition-s-dirty-little-secret-millions-online-photos-scraped-n981921&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;someone adds your kids to a facial recognition database without your consent.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;backing-up-cell-phones&quot;&gt;Backing up cell phones&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a lot of options for backing up what’s on your cell phone, and honestly most of them are terrible. So I’m not going to talk about them. Instead I’ll discuss what I do, which gets the photos and videos off my phone and into the backup process I described above in a fairly painless way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I use &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.resilio.com/individuals/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Reslio Sync&lt;/a&gt;’s Camera Backup feature to back up all the photos and videos on my family’s phones to my home computer. The setup is described &lt;a href=&quot;https://help.resilio.com/hc/en-us/articles/205506809-How-to-use-Camera-Backup-all-mobiles-&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; - basically you just install it on a PC as well as all your phones, and you’re off to the races. It copies over everything at its original quality and with original filenames, and once it’s on your PC you can just back it up as you do everything else following the 3-2-1 rule.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;One important caveat:&lt;/strong&gt; Resilio Sync has to be running to back things up. So you need to remember to run it periodically. And you’ll want to be on Wifi when you do, because our phones nowadays generate some pretty big files.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;backing-up-more-than-one-computer&quot;&gt;Backing up more than one computer&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What if you’ve got more than one computer? You could duplicate the above steps for each machine, but that can get cumbersome. I prefer designating one machine as primary, backing up the others to that one, and then using that as my single entry into my 3-2-1 system. I’m already doing that with our cellphones - both my and my wife’s phones back up to my PC, and from there the folders go to Backblaze and my local backup as usual.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To accomplish this with PC’s, I once again turn to Resilio Sync. I have my wife’s laptop set to sync her Documents and Desktop folders to my PC automatically. Laptop gets stolen? Her CAD files are all safely at home, with no user intervention required. So while we have multiple computers and two phones, all the data still ends up in one spot for organization and backup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The downside of this is that it’s not feasible if you have multiple machines that all have large amounts of data. At a certain point, you just won’t be able to centralize it all to one machine. But for most families I feel that centralizing is pretty easily doable, and then gives you a single source from which to admin your 3-2-1 process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;keep-it-up&quot;&gt;Keep it up&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everything I’ve described here is an ongoing process. You’re always generating new data, and so you need to also be continuously backing up that data. Set yourself a reminder to copy things to that external drive - this is also a good time to confirm that Backblaze (or whichever cloud provider you use) is still doing its thing in the background. I do this about once a month, unless I have something critical to back up (like say wedding or baby photos).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You should also be prepared to replace drives every 3-5 years (that’s statistically when they die). Since your data is in more than one place, you can technically wait until a drive actually dies to replace it - just don’t wait too much longer after that, as your data is at greater risk until you get back up to 3 locations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And don’t forget to test this stuff! Many a sysadmin has been burned by cloud backups they never checked until the other data locations were gone. Periodically download your cloud backups and make sure they’re all there and as expected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;thats-it&quot;&gt;That’s it!&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Follow the above steps and you’ll be able to sleep soundly knowing that your data is in very little danger of vanishing on you. And if you ever need that animated gif of your friend with a plate of nachos from a decade ago, you’re covered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;kg-card kg-image-card&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/posts/Nick_Nachos.gif&quot; class=&quot;kg-image&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content><author><name>Chris Ostertag</name></author><category term="home" /><category term="words" /><summary type="html">We collectively generate over a trillion digital photos a year. Don&apos;t lose them.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Chili Crisp Benedict</title><link href="/benedict/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Chili Crisp Benedict" /><published>2023-12-26T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2023-12-26T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>/benedict</id><content type="html" xml:base="/benedict/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/recipes/benedict.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;a photo of two rice patties topped with sliced pork, eggs, a drizzle of pink sauce, and green onions, all on a bright green plate&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s something to do with day-old rice besides fried rice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;ingredients&quot;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;3 eggs&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 cup day-old cooked rice&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 tbsp &lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/3NFNHHT&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Lao Gan Ma chili crisp&lt;/a&gt; (you will end up using this stuff on everything once it’s in your house)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;bacon or pork (I use smoked pork loin)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;sliced green onions and &lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/3RVSZBr&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Sriracha Mayo&lt;/a&gt; for garnish&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;preparation&quot;&gt;Preparation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Combine one cup rice, one egg, and one tbsp Lao Gan Ma in a food processor or blender. Process until your rice grains are about half their starting size and everything is well mixed.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Shape into two patties, pan fry until crispy, then set aside.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Brown whatever meat you’re using, set aside on top of the rice patties.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cook two eggs however you like them (I do them over easy for this)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Put the eggs on top of the pork and rice patties&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Garnish with green onions and Sriracha Mayo&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Eat it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content><author><name>Chris Ostertag</name></author><category term="recipe" /><category term="home" /><category term="breakfast" /><summary type="html">An interesting and flavorful way to use old rice</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Password Expiration Policies Don’t Work</title><link href="/password-expiration/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Password Expiration Policies Don’t Work" /><published>2022-12-02T19:03:05-06:00</published><updated>2022-12-02T19:03:05-06:00</updated><id>/password-expiration</id><content type="html" xml:base="/password-expiration/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.unsplash.com/photo-1633265486064-086b219458ec?crop=entropy&amp;amp;cs=tinysrgb&amp;amp;fit=max&amp;amp;fm=jpg&amp;amp;ixid=MnwxMTc3M3wwfDF8c2VhcmNofDF8fHBhc3N3b3JkfGVufDB8fHx8MTY3MDAwNzczNQ&amp;amp;ixlib=rb-4.0.3&amp;amp;q=80&amp;amp;w=2000&quot; alt=&quot;a stock photo of a combinatino lock laying on a laptop keyboard&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It seems some auditors are still asking organizations to rotate passwords periodically in the name of “current industry standard.” Below are some resources that you can use to show that arbitrary time-based password expiration is no longer best practice and hasn’t been for some time. Are there cases where you might want to still implement such a policy? Sure! But it is not, by any means, a universal standard that all organizations will benefit from.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;nist&quot;&gt;NIST&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;NIST, the organization that most of these audits peg their rules to, revised their guidance at least two years ago to no longer recommend periodic password changes: &lt;a href=&quot;https://pages.nist.gov/800-63-FAQ/#q-b05&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;https://pages.nist.gov/800-63-FAQ/#q-b05&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://pages.nist.gov/800-63-3/sp800-63b.html#memsecretver&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;SP 800-63B Section 5.1.1.2&lt;/a&gt; paragraph 9 states:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Verifiers SHOULD NOT require memorized secrets to be changed arbitrarily (e.g., periodically). However, verifiers SHALL force a change if there is evidence of compromise of the authenticator.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Users tend to choose weaker memorized secrets when they know that they will have to change them in the near future. When those changes do occur, they often select a secret that is similar to their old memorized secret by applying a set of common transformations such as increasing a number in the password. This practice provides a false sense of security if any of the previous secrets has been compromised since attackers can apply these same common transformations. But if there is evidence that the memorized secret has been compromised, such as by a breach of the verifier’s hashed password database or observed fraudulent activity, subscribers should be required to change their memorized secrets. However, this event-based change should occur rarely, so that they are less motivated to choose a weak secret with the knowledge that it will only be used for a limited period of time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;microsoft&quot;&gt;Microsoft&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Microsoft changed their guidance on the topic in 2019: &lt;a href=&quot;https://learn.microsoft.com/en-us/archive/blogs/secguide/security-baseline-final-for-windows-10-v1903-and-windows-server-v1903&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;https://learn.microsoft.com/en-us/archive/blogs/secguide/security-baseline-final-for-windows-10-v1903-and-windows-server-v1903&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;federal-trade-commission&quot;&gt;Federal Trade Commission&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2016, the FTC highlighted research that shows that mandatory periodic password changes do not improve security and may even harm it: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ftc.gov/policy/advocacy-research/tech-at-ftc/2016/03/time-rethink-mandatory-password-changes&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;https://www.ftc.gov/policy/advocacy-research/tech-at-ftc/2016/03/time-rethink-mandatory-password-changes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;national-cyber-security-centre&quot;&gt;National Cyber Security Centre&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The UK National Cyber Security Centre likewise changed their policy recommendation to discourage periodic password changes: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncsc.gov.uk/collection/passwords/updating-your-approach&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;https://www.ncsc.gov.uk/collection/passwords/updating-your-approach&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Chris Ostertag</name></author><category term="it" /><category term="security" /><category term="home" /><category term="words" /><summary type="html">Arbitrary time-based password expiration is not an industry best practice and has not been for years.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Ubiquiti US-16-XG Beta - Invalid Firmware Fix</title><link href="/ubiquiti-us-16-xg-beta-invalid-firmware-fix/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Ubiquiti US-16-XG Beta - Invalid Firmware Fix" /><published>2021-05-01T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2021-05-01T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>/ubiquiti-us-16-xg-beta-invalid-firmware-fix</id><content type="html" xml:base="/ubiquiti-us-16-xg-beta-invalid-firmware-fix/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/posts/unifi-switch-16xg-features-ports2x1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;a photo of a silver Ubiquiti US-16-XG switch&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;UPDATE 2021-05&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The links in the original post died. Luckily, a helpful friend named Guillermo shot me an email with the updated firmwares you’ll need.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First update to this one: &lt;a href=&quot;http://dl.ubnt-ut.com/usw/US.bcm5341x.develop.10223.190407.1857-uboot.bin&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;http://dl.ubnt-ut.com/usw/US.bcm5341x.develop.10223.190407.1857-uboot.bin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then update to this one: &lt;a href=&quot;http://dl.ui.com/unifi/firmware/USXG/5.43.35.12698/US.bcm5341x_5.43.35+12698.210326.0445.bin&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;http://dl.ui.com/unifi/firmware/USXG/5.43.35.12698/US.bcm5341x_5.43.35+12698.210326.0445.bin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keep in mind I have not personally tested the above path, so YMMV.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Original post is below for posterity. Thanks Guillermo!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;ORIGINAL POST&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A while back we picked up a couple &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ubnt.com/unifi-switching/unifi-switch-16-xg/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Ubiquiti US-16-XG&lt;/a&gt; switches for $299 each during their beta period. These are 10G switches, 12 SFP+’s and 4 RJ45’s, at a pretty crazy price. But then I got busy and didn’t mess with one until now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since some time has passed, the US-16-XG is now out of beta. And &lt;a href=&quot;https://community.ubnt.com/t5/UniFi-Routing-Switching/US-16-XG-out-of-beta/m-p/1799010&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;nothing has changed in hardware&lt;/a&gt;, so upgrade the firmware and you got the production product for half off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Easier said than done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unifi didn’t give me the Upgrade option, and I kept getting Invalid Firmware and Invalid Version errors when doing it manually.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Solution – I had to put transitional firmware on it:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://community.ubnt.com/t5/UniFi-Routing-Switching-Beta/US-16-XG-Transitional-Firmware/m-p/1758381/highlight/true#M819&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;https://community.ubnt.com/t5/UniFi-Routing-Switching-Beta/US-16-XG-Transitional-Firmware/m-p/1758381/highlight/true#M819&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using the SSH method:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://help.ubnt.com/hc/en-us/articles/204910064-UniFi-Upgrading-firmware-image-via-SSH#standard%20upgrade&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;https://help.ubnt.com/hc/en-us/articles/204910064-UniFi-Upgrading-firmware-image-via-SSH#standard%20upgrade&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Only after I did that could I update the firmware properly via Unifi.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’ve already adopted the switch in Unifi, the SSH creds are the same as you use for Unifi. If not adopted, it’s the default ubnt/ubnt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m posting this solely because it took me hours to track down the thing about the transitional firmware. Hopefully you got here after having wasted less time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And hey, now you have a $599 switch that you got for $299!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Chris Ostertag</name></author><category term="tech" /><category term="ubiquiti" /><category term="words" /><summary type="html">A solution to an extremely specific and obscure problem.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Hoppin’ John</title><link href="/hoppin-john/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hoppin’ John" /><published>2020-01-05T20:05:21-06:00</published><updated>2020-01-05T20:05:21-06:00</updated><id>/hoppin-john</id><content type="html" xml:base="/hoppin-john/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/recipes/HoppinJohn.png&quot; alt=&quot;a closeup photo of a pile of black-eyed peas&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This dish is very filling, and makes a lot, so you might want to halve the recipe the first time you make it. I also don’t serve this over rice but you do you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Need to make it a side? Omit the pork and add a bit more liquid. Instructions for both are below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I make mine in an &lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/31tPQeS&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Instant Pot&lt;/a&gt;. You can do it in a crockpot too, it’ll just take a lot longer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;ingredients&quot;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 tbsp extra light olive oil (or whatever you cook with, just nothing too flavorful)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;3 slices bacon, diced&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 onion, diced&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;4 carrots, peeled and diced&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 poblano peppers, diced&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 garlic cloves, minced&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/4 tsp cayenne pepper&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 tsp dried thyme&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 tsp salt&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/2 tsp freshly ground black pepper&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 lb dried black-eyed peas, rinsed and quick-soaked (see note below) or soaked overnight&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 lb pork, cut into small pieces (optional but see note below)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 cups chicken stock (3 if not using pork)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;beans-quick-soak&quot;&gt;Beans Quick Soak&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rinse thoroughly and pick out rocks and whatever&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Put in Instant Pot with 1 cup of water for every 2oz of dried beans (so 8 cups for this recipe)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bring to a boil on the Sauté setting with the cover off&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Once boiling, put the lid on and cook at High Pressure for 2 minutes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Quick release, drain peas, put aside&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;preparation&quot;&gt;Preparation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Heat up the oil in the Instant Pot on the Sauté setting&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add bacon, cook until brown and a little crispy&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add onion, carrots, pepper, and garlic. Cook until onions are mostly translucent, stirring often.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add the rest of the ingredients and stir well to combine&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lock the lid and cook on High Pressure for 15 minutes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Quick Release&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Eat it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content><author><name>Chris Ostertag</name></author><category term="recipe" /><category term="home" /><summary type="html">A side dish or a full meal, tasty either way</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Jennie’s Zucchini Soup</title><link href="/zucchini-soup/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Jennie’s Zucchini Soup" /><published>2019-11-12T04:37:38-06:00</published><updated>2019-11-12T04:37:38-06:00</updated><id>/zucchini-soup</id><content type="html" xml:base="/zucchini-soup/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/recipes/ZukeSoup.png&quot; alt=&quot;Zucchini Soup&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Basically all you do is barely chop the ingredients and throw them in the pot. You don’t need an &lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/2X6MrC6&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;immersion blender&lt;/a&gt; but it’s easier with one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I should also note that I hate zucchini and still love this soup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;ingredients&quot;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;32 oz chicken broth&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 slice thick-cut bacon, finely chopped&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 onion, quartered&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;3 zucchini, skin on, cut into large chunks&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;4 oz dried black eyed peas (no need to pre-soak)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 cloves garlic, minced&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Big handful of fresh basil (or 1 tbsp dried basil)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;preparation&quot;&gt;Preparation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Combine all ingredients in Instant Pot&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cook on High Pressure for 2 minutes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Quick release, immersion blend until smooth (or transfer to a blender)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Serve with a good crusty bread (I do asiago rolls)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Eat it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content><author><name>Chris Ostertag</name></author><category term="recipe" /><category term="home" /><summary type="html">Basically all you do is barely chop the ingredients and throw them in the pot</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Video Grandpa Margarita</title><link href="/margarita/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Video Grandpa Margarita" /><published>2019-10-19T02:47:55-05:00</published><updated>2019-10-19T02:47:55-05:00</updated><id>/margarita</id><content type="html" xml:base="/margarita/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://source.unsplash.com/S4cdTe1Jx04&quot; alt=&quot;a top-down photo of a glass of greenish liquid with ice and green leaf garnish, by https://unsplash.com/@brianna_santellan&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;regular-version&quot;&gt;Regular Version&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2.5 oz 100% agave silver tequila, like &lt;a href=&quot;https://specsonline.com/shop/spirits/alteno-tequila-silver-100-agave/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Messicano Alteño Silver&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
0.5 oz &lt;a href=&quot;https://specsonline.com/shop/spirits/del-maguey-mezcal-vida-6-case/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Del Maguey Vida&lt;/a&gt; mezcal&lt;br /&gt;
1 oz fresh lime juice&lt;br /&gt;
0.5 oz agave nectar&lt;br /&gt;
Rocks&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;jalapeño-version&quot;&gt;Jalapeño Version&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3 oz 100% agave silver tequila, like &lt;a href=&quot;https://specsonline.com/shop/spirits/alteno-tequila-silver-100-agave/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Messicano Alteño Silver&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt; 
0.5 oz jalapeño juice&lt;br /&gt;
1 oz fresh lime juice&lt;br /&gt;
0.5 oz agave nectar&lt;br /&gt;
Rocks&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Chris Ostertag</name></author><category term="recipe" /><summary type="html">There are many margarita recipes. This is mine. Down with triple sec.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Video Grandpa’s Chili Recipe</title><link href="/chili/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Video Grandpa’s Chili Recipe" /><published>2019-10-18T14:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-10-18T14:00:00-05:00</updated><id>/chili</id><content type="html" xml:base="/chili/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/recipes/Chili.png&quot; alt=&quot;a close-up of a sliced jalapeno sitting on top of chili and cheese&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A smoky chili you can easily make in a crock pot or Instant Pot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s loosely based on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sunset.com/recipe/smoky-beef-and-bacon-chili&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;one from Sunset magazine&lt;/a&gt; – mine tastes better and is made in a crock pot or &lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/31tPQeS&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Instant Pot&lt;/a&gt; so it takes basically no work. It’s not too spicy and can be enjoyed by everyone. If you want to kick up the spice I’d say either add more hot paprika or some jalapeños before cooking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;ingredients&quot;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 pound beef, cut into small chunks (I use lean stew beef from HEB)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;4 slices thick-cut bacon, finely chopped&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 large onion, finely chopped&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 large garlic clove, minced&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 large can (28 oz.) diced tomatoes, drained completely&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 cup flavorful medium-bodied beer (&lt;a href=&quot;https://realalebrewing.com/beers/firemans-4/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Fireman’s 4&lt;/a&gt; obviously)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;8oz (1 cup) dried black beans or red kidney beans (we prefer black)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 tbsp chili powder&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 1/2 tsp ground cumin&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 1/2 tsp sweet paprika&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/2 tsp hot paprika&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 tsp cayenne pepper&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1.5 tsp salt (smoked salt is best)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 tsp Worcestershire sauce&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 tsp liquid smoke&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;preparation-in-crock-pot&quot;&gt;Preparation in Crock Pot&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Combine all ingredients in crock pot&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cook on low for 6-8 hours&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 hour before serving, stir and break up beef&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Garnish w cheese and jalapeños&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Eat it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;preparation-in-instant-pot&quot;&gt;Preparation in Instant Pot&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Combine all ingredients in Instant Pot&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cook on High Pressure for 45 minutes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Quick release, stir and break up beef&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Saute for a bit to cook down some of the liquid, stirring frequently&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Garnish w cheese and jalapenos&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Eat it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content><author><name>Chris Ostertag</name></author><category term="recipe" /><category term="home" /><summary type="html">There are many chili recipes. This is mine.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Everything is Digital</title><link href="/everything-is-digital/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Everything is Digital" /><published>2018-09-24T13:04:49-05:00</published><updated>2018-09-24T13:04:49-05:00</updated><id>/everything-is-digital</id><content type="html" xml:base="/everything-is-digital/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.unsplash.com/photo-1526374965328-7f61d4dc18c5?ixlib=rb-1.2.1&amp;amp;q=80&amp;amp;fm=jpg&amp;amp;crop=edges&amp;amp;cs=tinysrgb&amp;amp;fit=max&amp;amp;ixid=eyJhcHBfaWQiOjExNzczfQ&amp;amp;w=1000&quot; alt=&quot;green vertical rows of text characters on a black background&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stop saying “digital.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know, it’s hard. A lot of work has been put into convincing ourselves that these silos exist. We ask questions like “how many digital staff do you have?” We use “just for web” as an excuse to do lesser work with cheap gear. The teams supporting on-air and online barely speak, or maybe the latter doesn’t even exist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But these lines are made-up, and they’re holding us back. We are in the business of content creation and distribution. The sooner we get away from arbitrarily scope-limiting everything from the get-go, the better off we’ll be. Over-the-air broadcasting is just an MPEG2 live stream delivered via RF. A web short is just an interstitial with different white and black levels. A podcast is a radio show.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Content is content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And what it takes to create content that resonates with an audience does not change. Authenticity, trust, professionalism – these are the hallmarks of the PBS system. And as it turns out, these are also what audiences – all audiences – are most looking for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But when we choose not to put something online, or not to produce something if it’s “just for web,” we are choosing not to serve an audience. And the audience we’re choosing not to serve is critical to our future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The clearest trend in media is that broadcast viewership is declining by generation. Look, here’s a chart:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;kg-card kg-image-card kg-card-hascaption&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/posts/Nielsen-Traditional-TV-Viewing-by-Age-Q12011-Q22017-Dec2017-1-.png&quot; class=&quot;kg-image&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.marketingcharts.com/featured-24817&quot;&gt;https://www.marketingcharts.com/featured-24817&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are other charts like it, and they all show the same thing. Slowly but surely, our on-air viewership is dwindling and will not be replenished. Which begs the obvious question: who’s going to fund all the stuff we do in the future?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thankfully, we’re already seeing the answer through Passport. Products like Passport appeal to shifting behavior in younger donors. Younger donors &lt;a href=&quot;https://ssir.org/book_reviews/entry/show_me_the_impact&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;seek direct impact from their philanthropic giving&lt;/a&gt;, like to support &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.themillennialimpact.com/sites/default/files/reports/Phase2Report_MIR2017_091917_0.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;local causes over national&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.themillennialimpact.com/sites/default/files/reports/Phase2Report_MIR2017_091917_0.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;prefer to give online&lt;/a&gt;, and are &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.marketingcharts.com/featured-24817&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;trending away from watching broadcast television&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stations that aren’t treating the online space with the same seriousness as on-air are purposely short-changing the audience that will be their donor base into the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So why don’t we just do it? Commit to being where our audiences are?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of it’s based on assumptions long proven false. The biggest one I hear again and again is the fear of cannibalization. But viewer cannibalization has been proven repeatedly to be a myth. Online viewers are in addition to on-air viewers, not in place of. We don’t even see much evidence of cannibalization between online platforms – YouTube and COVE, for example. Audiences are where they want to be. We either meet them there or lose them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The online quality drop is also a myth. When done properly, online content will look better than on-air. Full stop. YouTubers like MKBHD &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/z3X49SYvbo0?t=1m15s&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;are shooting 8K RAW&lt;/a&gt; so their content is ready for re-use on future platforms. Meanwhile, we’re still sending out 1080i compressed into MPEG2. At a technical level, it’s not even close.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But some of it is inertia, and that’s a lot harder to overcome. As a relative newcomer to the PBS system, the number of times I’ve heard “why do we do this?” answered with “we’ve always done this” is staggering. The online space can be confusing, with all those kids asking “What’s up, guys?” directly into the camera. But to the previous point, we have a massive advantage in that we don’t have to chase the latest trends or hottest keywords. Authenticity, trust, professionalism – we’ve spend decades building that foundation. We just need to show it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, there’s the financial issue. This may feel like the hardest to overcome, especially for small stations. But it’s also, in a way, the simplest: do you want to exist in 20 years? If yes, then it’s time to make some hard choices about resource allocations. We have to embrace all of our audiences if we are to survive. Think of it this way: if your tower falls down, or encoder catches fire, is there a choice?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stop saying “digital.” Everything is digital. We adapt or we die.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This article originally appeared in PBS TechNews&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Chris Ostertag</name></author><category term="strategy" /><category term="home" /><category term="words" /><summary type="html">Arbitrary distinctions are arbitrary.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Why Should I Caption Online-Only Content?</title><link href="/why-should-i-caption-online-only-content/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Why Should I Caption Online-Only Content?" /><published>2018-02-26T12:22:32-06:00</published><updated>2018-02-26T12:22:32-06:00</updated><id>/why-should-i-caption-online-only-content</id><content type="html" xml:base="/why-should-i-caption-online-only-content/">&lt;p&gt;Do we really have to caption online-only content? I want to caption everything, but how do I justify it to my organization when technically we may not have to?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a great but surprisingly complicated question. So let’s take a look at the current rules, then go beyond them to get the whole answer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-current-rules&quot;&gt;The Current Rules&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The current FCC regulations around closed captioning of online video &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fcc.gov/consumers/guides/captioning-internet-video-programming&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;can be found here&lt;/a&gt;. The most important part is this one:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“The Internet closed captioning rules only apply if the video programming was shown on TV in the U.S. with captions.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s how the FCC has any enforcement power at all – it’s predicated on the content being shown on TV with captions. If that’s never happened, there is no online captioning requirement &lt;em&gt;from the FCC&lt;/em&gt; (that last part will be important later).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So if you’re just looking for a quick easy answer, and you’re primarily regulated by the FCC, you could stop here. If it hasn’t been shown on TV with captions, it’s not required to have captions online. Cut and dry. Right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wrong! There’s more to it than that, and if you stop here, you’ve missed the whole picture. There are compelling reasons beyond the FCC that you should be captioning your online video.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-other-regulatory-reason&quot;&gt;The (Other) Regulatory Reason&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remember that &lt;em&gt;from the FCC&lt;/em&gt; part like 4 sentences ago? Those italics indicate the presence of a looming gotcha!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While there may not be an FCC requirement for captions on your content, the regulatory landscape is always changing, and right now the winds are blowing in a way that could impact everyone who does online video. It all comes down to how important the online space has become in our public lives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2010, the National Association of the Deaf brought a lawsuit against Netflix, arguing that they were violating the Americans with Disabilities Act because a website is a “place of public accommodation” (a specific term in the ADA) and thus video needs to have closed captions. The court agreed and allowed the lawsuit to move forward. Netflix settled and agreed to caption all of its content. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.3playmedia.com/2013/09/27/the-ada-online-video-captioning-standards/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;More info here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was big. Really big. A court agreeing that a website is “a place of public accommodation” opens the door to a whole lot of regulatory interpretations – among them a closed caption requirement for video.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But then a different court did the exact opposite! In 2 different cases, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.3playmedia.com/2016/06/08/earll-v-ebay-is-a-website-a-place-of-public-accommodation/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;the 9th Circuit ruled&lt;/a&gt; that websites are NOT places of public accommodation. And one of those cases was about Netflix captions. But that one was unpublished, so it’s not meant to be cited as precedent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.3playmedia.com/2015/06/27/usdoj-sides-with-nad-in-web-accessibility-lawsuit-against-harvard-mit/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;another lawsuit&lt;/a&gt;, the Department of Justice weighed in and said this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“The ADA applies to websites of public accommodations, and…the ADA regulations should be interpreted to keep pace with developing technologies.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m sure I’ve missed other cases – these are just the big ones that always get talked about. So what do we do?!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Basically, the overall regulatory question is far from settled, but it’s something that you need to be aware of and following if you’re working in online video. My best advice is to consult your lawyer, which is what you should do every time you’re presented with a murky legal question that has far-reaching implications for your business. And keep up on cases involving the ADA and online video, and specifically ones that touch on the definition of public accommodation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But if you watch how people discuss websites, especially in the wake of the information warfare surrounding the 2016 US election, I think you can see a trend. Take this tweet from the head of the FCC, where he calls online platforms “America’s public square.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;kg-card kg-embed-card&quot;&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot;&gt;
&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;How is social media affecting American society? I offered some thoughts &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/TheMediaInst?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;@TheMediaInst&lt;/a&gt; on civility, politics, and in-person interaction as online platforms become America&apos;s public square. &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/AF7eB8tdjA&quot;&gt;https://t.co/AF7eB8tdjA&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Ajit Pai (@AjitPaiFCC) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/AjitPaiFCC/status/936050444685774848?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;November 30, 2017&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My personal opinion: I think it’s only a matter of time until websites are considered a place of public accommodation, with all the rights and requirements that come along with that distinction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;_ &lt;strong&gt;2019-10-07 Update:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.abajournal.com/news/article/supreme-court-rejects-dominos-appeal-over-web-and-app-accessibility&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;SCOTUS just declined to hear the appeal&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.scotusblog.com/case-files/cases/dominos-pizza-llc-v-robles/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Domino’s Pizza LLC v. Robles&lt;/a&gt;, which means the &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.ca9.uscourts.gov/datastore/opinions/2019/01/15/17-55504.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;9th Circuit’s decision&lt;/a&gt; stands. The decision quotes &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/National_Federation_of_the_Blind_v._Target_Corp.&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;a previous one&lt;/a&gt; and restates:_&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The statute applies to the services of a place of public accommodation, not services in a place of public accommodation. To limit the ADA to discrimination in the provision of services occurring on the premises of a public accommodation would contradict the plain language of the statute.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-metadata-reason&quot;&gt;The Metadata Reason&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe your lawyer has reviewed everything I just said and decided I’m dead wrong. It’s cool, it happens sometimes. But there’s another reason to caption everything you do: you’re creating rich metadata with long-term value.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Captions give you a record of every word that’s spoken in your content. And when you pair them with a video platform, all that data becomes searchable. If a viewer’s looking for something specific that gets mentioned in your video, but you don’t include it in the metadata, their only chance of finding it is if you’d included a caption file. For example, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.3playmedia.com/2016/03/07/5-quick-tips-for-youtube-seo-strategy/&quot;&gt;YouTube indexes caption files and includes their content in search&lt;/a&gt;, but only if you upload one yourself – they do NOT index the auto-generated captions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is also helpful for internal use. Need to cut together a video of every time someone said a certain word on your show? Or highlight times in the past where a politician has spoken on a certain issue? It’s trivially easy to track down those moments if you’ve got captions. At my shop we’re working on an archive of all of &lt;em&gt;Austin City Limits&lt;/em&gt;, and it’s pretty magic to be able to search for how many times someone has said “Texas” on the show.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-human-reason&quot;&gt;The Human Reason&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When considering regulations and value adds, sometimes we lose sight of the simple reason: it’s the right thing to do. If you’ve ever helped someone who’s visually or hearing impaired navigate media consumption, you know how awful it is out there. Company after company, provider after provider, does the absolute bare minimum or finds a loophole so they don’t even have to do that. I recently encountered a cable box where you had to be able to see to turn on the options for people who can’t see. And this level of “we don’t care at all” is not rare.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So maybe when we consider these things, we should think about what a big impact a relatively small amount of effort can have for some people who are already struggling to enjoy things many of us take for granted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-cost-reason&quot;&gt;The Cost Reason&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve saved the simplest reason for last: it costs &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rev.com/caption&quot;&gt;$1 per minute&lt;/a&gt; to caption your content. That’s nothing in a production budget. Even ignoring everything else above, it’s now so cheap to caption content that by &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; doing it, you’re saying to the world that you won’t even put in the smallest effort to make your content accessible to everyone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that makes you the asshole.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t be the asshole. Caption your content.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Chris Ostertag</name></author><category term="distribution" /><category term="featured" /><category term="post-production" /><category term="production" /><category term="home" /><category term="closed-captions" /><category term="words" /><summary type="html">Don&apos;t be an asshole.</summary></entry></feed>